Despite what everyone tells you online,
getting 100K a month, 200K a month,
Lamborghini SVJ, Porsche GT3 RS,
the real thing that everyone watching this
should
aspire for is an extra $2,000 a month.
And once you find an extra $2,000 a month,
everything changes.
And I don't think we're giving enough
credit to how much of a change that is.
So right here is a graph.
I'm not actually sure
if Declan's managed to
green screen it behind me,
or maybe he's having a tough day in the
edit and he's
just put it in front of you.
But there used to be analytics in
Facebook, which was
my main social media platform,
and this was a snapshot I took the day I
hit
40,000 followers.
This page has now got 1.1 million,
my Insta's got 1.4
million, TikTok's got 1.8 million. Sorry,
that's an appeal to authority.
You do that to people so they start
listening to what you're saying.
It's why personal trainers get their tops
off when they're talking about stuff.
You subconsciously put their physique
and what they're saying together.
Same reason that business coaches often
sit in their nice car.
But anyway, back to the graph.
Consider this line that's going down the
middle is
20,000 followers. You'll realize
that for almost all of the time, I had
no following. Now,
an interesting thing in this graph is
that this actually started
in 2014.
I passed my PT certification April
2014,
and that was the day I started posting.
Now,
the reason I'm showing you this graph
is to remind you, you are not special.
And I think some of you go through life
maybe a bit disillusioned, maybe you've
listened to too many Stephen Bartlett
podcasts, I don't know.
And I posted every single day
and got no growth.
I had so many opportunities to be
frustrated.
And the interesting thing is here,
let's say you meet me in summer 2016.
Let's say August.
You would think I'm fucking mental.
You would say, "All right, mate,
so you've been posting every day for two
years and
you've got 3,000 followers. Cool.
Nice one." Do you know how many online
clients I had? Zero.
Do you know how many things I'd sold?
Zero. You would have thought I was mental.
If you met me a year later in 2017, "Mate,
you're blowing up.
How did you become an overnight success?"
But if we go back to the graph quickly,
you'll notice there
is a little bump in October,
and then after that, everything
takes off.
And I've never really told people about
this before.
That bump in October was
when I secured an extra
$2,000 a month. And in this video,
I'm going to explain to you exactly how
that happened and how you can apply this
to your own business and your own journey,
whether a personal trainer or not.
Now, very quickly,
the only link in the description for this
video is I've put
together 30 ways in 30 days to improve
your business.
So basically,
you give me your email address,
and every day over the next month, I
give you a little bit of a nugget,
and you go, "Jesus Christ,
never thought of it
like that before."
And why it's important
that you just pause the video now and go
sign up for that for 45 seconds will
become clearer in the video. Twofold.
One, you'll realize
that the most important thing in this
video is that I get your
data. The second thing
is you need to copy what I'm about to do
with you over those
next few days. Cool.
If you didn't click on that link,
you're a fucking idiot.
But anyway, moving on.
Just to get this point home,
let's go back to
2014. I think it's very important
that you guys see this. All right.
Where's this post? 1st of April, 2014,
two likes.
This is where I started my personal
training journey.
Like I told you, April 2014. Now,
what you have here is thousands
of repetitions of me making terrible
posts, completely misjudging my audience,
having no idea what I'm doing.
Here,
I'm taking a screenshot of MyFitnessPal.
"Food logging may not work for everyone.
I find that it's an effective way of
measuring my mac..." Well done, James.
Great post, bro. Fantastic.
I am the guy that you
would want to take the piss out of.
There's food prep here.
Like someone's going to see me putting
fucking veggies and chicken in Tupperware
and thinking, "Wow,
how the hell do I follow you?"
But the thing is, I even post
memes. Should I work out today? Yes.
Go work out. No. Yes, you should.
But at least when I did this,
every single post
that I made gave me feedback.
It gave me an idea of whether
or not someone was interested.
I would tell people how many teaspoons of
sugar are in a fucking
orange juice or whatever it is,
explaining what fat grips are.
I think I was using these in a workout,
so I was like, "Do you know what?
I'll just post about it." Four likes.
If I saw something in the newspaper,
I'd just take a
picture, do a little post. And again,
these are the things, the repetitions,
that none of you ever saw.
You just see it now. Oh, here you go.
I put this together,
a summer body 10-week transformation.
And guess what? No one did it.
No one really bought it
or anything because I had
no idea what I was doing.
There's my old branding, by the way, JS
Training. Used to hide behind a brand.
Don't do that. This is just awful.
There's some fun stuff from Dubai Sevens
or whatever.
And what have I put here? Okay.
If you want to know more about my
training program, cool.
But you'll notice something here that's
quite interesting.
We'll get into this in a second.
That's me telling people to sign up to my
email
list. 10 years ago. 10 years ago.
Before videos, I would
pretty much...
Lifting weights made me look manly.
No one ever.
Fantastic. James, what a hero you are.
But through all these hundreds of
repetitions that it gets to, you start
to understand what posts do well
and what posts don't, and you start
to realize and resonate your audience
and what they're looking for
and what helps
them and what doesn't. And ultimately,
it is only through doing
these huge amounts of repetitions
that you get to understand your audience
at all. Now, I started off doing this.
Many of you think you get to skip this
part. You don't.
And this is embarrassing for me to go back
and look at. This is so embarrassing.
But then over time,
as I start to learn my audience and make
micro-calculations,
I start to make things
that perform better.
This one, 1,000 likes because it was easy.
Just a little picture on the board.
Let's keep going a little bit further.
Repetitions, repetitions, repetitions. Oh,
would you look at that?
My first talk at BodyPower.
Don't be a massive cunt.
Some people know what that's about,
other people don't.
It took me ages to go back to go find
those,
but I wanted to show you because you
might see me, here you go, James
is competent on camera,
knows what he's doing,
makes amazing YouTube videos,
is incredibly good-looking. Sure.
But I had to eat shit
and do the hard yards and fucking suck
and do embarrassing
shit and take pictures of my lunch.
What makes you think you
are so special that you don't have to?
That's my point.
The day that I qualified,
I started investing.
But investing in stocks and shares
and ETFs, you need a surplus of money,
which I
never had. The only thing I had was time.
I decided I was going to invest a weird
traditional way of just
45 minutes a day just putting a post out
there. I don't want anything back from it.
Similar to if you put money in stocks
and shares now,
it's pretty retarded to think
you'll get anything back in a week
or a month.
You'd be like, "Right, but in years,
that could work for me." This
is what social
media is. It's the exact same.
Me back then, I was like,
"If I just put in 45
minutes a day, in 5 or 10 years,
I will get that payment back." Now, if
I didn't invest anything in the stock
market, I can't complain in 10 years' time
when it hasn't compounded for me.
And in stocks and shares,
you need to invest for
20 or 30 years to get the return. But
if we go back to the graph, you'll
notice that in social media,
it only took me three years.
So that's 10 times faster than any return
that you could get by
investing into the traditional stock
market.
Better yet,
you get to fix this stock market,
because if I put money
into the S&P 500 today,
I can't influence if it does well or not.
But when I invest into social media I get
to control how well it does.
This video, this title, this thumbnail,
this strategy is all in my
control.
What I say over the next few minutes has
an impact to how many
people buy from me. How much money
is in my bank account at the end of the
month is
influenced by me.
I am insider trading in my own stock
market,
which is personal brand.
So your first lesson, pay in daily.
Imagine I give you a coupon every single
day.
You have the opportunity to either check
it in by making content or
chucking it in the bin. What
are you going to do? Guess what?
The more days you pay in,
the more you're going to compound
and the better return
you're going to get. Now,
lesson number two.
I remember back in the day when I
was flatlining, I
was listening to a podcast and
someone was asked their biggest regret,
and he said, "I didn't start an email list
early enough." I was like,
"What the hell is an email list?" Now,
an email list is
a way that you get to have contact with
people.
So for instance, before, when I said,
click on the link in the description
or the
comments and give me your email address
for 30 Ways in 30 Days, I'm opening a
second channel of conversations with you
because once you leave this video, you go,
"Fucking hell,
it's really insightful." I get to follow
up with bom, bom, bom, bom,
bom, knowledge. Over the next few weeks,
we get to create a relationship,
whether you come back to my content
or not.
You need to be doing this with other
people with your content.
Now,
the best time to start an email list
was 10 years ago, but the second
best time is now.
You can use a website like Kit, which
is one that I've just moved
to recently. It's fantastic. And again,
don't join my email list so you buy from
me. Join so you can steal
and copy what I'm doing.
Because the emotional connection me
and you are about to have over the next 30
days
is the same one you need to have with your
client.
Lesson number three would probably come
after that is, I'm so glad that my
email list was tiny
when I started emailing it because my
emails were
shit.
I remember writing an email to eight
subscribers, and I
remember I woke up in the morning
and I'd put too much laundry in the
laundry machine,
and I pulled out my PT top,
and it looked like someone had done
origami with it.
And I wrote it into an email,
and the point of the email was, I
gave my washing machine too much,
and it ended up ruining my clothes.
If I'd only put less in,
I would've got a better return.
Same with your training.
If you try giving yourself too much,
you're going to get a poor return.
Give your training to me,
join my online coaching, whatever it was.
Then let's bring that graph back up.
Sorry, Declan.
So October, let me tell you the thing
that happened.
I hit my 2K a month,
and I decided to burn the
fucking boats. Quite literally,
I went all in
online, and I flew one way to Australia.
And because I had my 2K online buffer,
I disregarded my entire
PT business, and I went all in.
I actually moved to Australia because I've
always
seen Sydney as like the epicenter of the
fitness industry.
I was like,
I'm not going to do this from Bracknell.
I either need to move to London
or a better city,
and I don't really like London.
So I was like, Sydney, bosh.
Now for 2K a week, I can feed myself,
sleep, have internet connection.
Now with those three things alone, that
is where the
waft came from. I went full time. Now,
every single
professional side will beat a part-time
side because the part-time side is trying
to juggle a job and play rugby in the
evenings. Full-time, you just play rugby.
No semi-pro team has won the premiership.
Big up the Saints for winning today,
by the way. Henry Pollock, what a bloke.
But here's the crazy part
that I think a lot of people overlook.
If we say 100K months,
you're so far away from that.
But when we say 2K months,
you might even still think you're far away
from it.
For me, it was 10 clients. 10 clients.
Even at flatline in that graph,
that works out to
0.4% of my audience because I had 2,500
followers.
If I said to you,
2,500 followers after three years of
posting content daily,
you would be bitterly disappointed with
that, but I'm not,
and I wasn't.
2K a month to not have to go to work.
Yeah, I was staying at backpackers. Yeah,
sure.
I wasn't exactly living good, but I
was happy because I could now go all in on
content creation.
And do you know what happens
when you go all in on content
creation?
You get fucking good at making content
very fucking
quickly because it's all you are doing.
I went full time.
Now,
let's quickly get into the economics
because some of you may not fully
grasp this yet. As we've made very clear,
all you need is an extra £2,000 a month.
From there, you can go all in,
you can burn the boats,
you can start to really
level up. But let's look at
that practically. 2,500 followers.
Now, let's try and say
that the golden rule,
as many of you will know, is 20% of
those we want on the email list. 10%
is 250, so that's 500.
500 people reading
and receiving my emails, of which I end up
with 10 clients. But now I'm full time,
and I'm paying the bills, and I've got
food, I've got shelter,
and I've got beers for the weekend.
My job just goes back up to this bit.
Then when this becomes 5,000,
this becomes 1,000,
this becomes 20.
And going from 2K to 4K a month,
my life just got so much better.
I'm buying a nicer camera.
I'm getting a microphone. And guess what?
I'm going to go straight back into doing
it again. Now, here's the other thing.
That's with me keeping the conversion
rates the same the whole way down.
But as you continue to do this,
you get better at content.
So this bit grows exponentially.
But then after that, you get better at
creating lead magnets because you're
getting signals from your content.
So the conversion rate increases
exponentially.
Then this is where the magic happens.
Eventually, you become full.
So you've become full,
you've got all the clients
that you can handle, and you've
done it whilst finessing every single
stage of the funnel.
And the best part is when you get full,
you get to raise prices.
When you get full,
you don't just stop working.
You increase your prices,
then you go back to the top of the funnel.
You create more content,
you get a bigger audience,
you grow your email list more.
And as you raise your prices,
you can even reduce the amount of people
that you
work with so you don't burn out,
which means you can go to the top,
you can create
more content,
you get more people on your email list.
Every single stage of this,
you just keep finessing.
You just keep getting better at.
After 2K a month,
it's just all about marginal
gains.
But the return on your investment just
compounds and compounds and
compounds. This should excite you so much.
The bit that sucks is getting to the 2K.
After that, it just gets better
and better.
So I went all in on content
when I hit that 2K a month, and I got the
unfair advantage.
Because I had worked through
that element of suck with all the
other personal trainers, and
when all the other personal trainers gave
up, I kept
going. I got to the 2K month.
I could then go all in on content,
and no one
else ever stood a chance Because all of my
competitors had to still do five
hours of personal training face-to-face a
day, which by the way, I started to miss
quite a bit, but I
was full-time online personal brand
making content, and they were part-time.
They were never going to be able to keep
up.
And then this is the thing
that a lot of people think they don't have
to do.
You need to become a content fucking
scientist.
Everything I learned in fitness,
I just applied to online.
I would watch someone do a new technique
in the gym and go, "Oh, I'll try that."
I'd look at someone do something different
with a cable, and I'd go, "Oh, I'll try
that tomorrow." Then I'd go, "Oh,
how does that feel? How's the pump?
How does the
muscle feel the next day? Oh,
it's quite good. I might add
that to my program.
Give it a go for four to six weeks,
then I'll either have it as part of my
regimen
or I won't." I would trial things with
different clients, some 20% deficit, some
10% deficit.
I was a scientist seeing what works better
for what person,
what works better for men,
what worked better for women.
Because it was all within my own best
interest, because the better I was as a
scientist with giving people exercise
and calorie or
nutritional programs,
the better their results,
the better my income.
So you have to be scientific in the world
of training.
That's how you're a good coach.
So then I was scientific in the world of
content.
Oh, I've seen that.
Seems to be working for them.
I'm going to try it.
How does it work? How did it do?
How did it perform?
How many emails did I get?
I'm going to do four to six weeks of this.
I'm going to try different things on
different platforms with different
demographics.
It's the exact same fucking thing.
Yet it takes years to become a good
personal trainer because you have to work
with
different clients.
Some do better than expected,
some do shit, some fail,
some exceed,
some bring you in more clients,
some you have to refund.
Where the fuck did you get lost in this
process thinking it was any different to
this? What fucking gurus
are you listening to online
that have detached you from
the reality of this,
where you think you can just go in
and win without all
of the clients that you failed before?
At 2K a month,
you get to give it everything
and become a full-time fucking content
scientist with unlimited repetitions at
the table, unlimited
spins, and some of them win.
The better odds than any other house
or any
stock market.
And the biggest problem here,
it's not the economy, it's not
GLP-1s, it's not the algorithm, it's you.
And I'm sorry,
but I think you may think you
are more special than
everyone else, and you may think
that you don't have to go through every
other fucking hurdle
that everyone else did.
And I'm here to remind you that you do.
Now,
I know not all of you understand Brazilian
jujitsu, but just listen to what
I'm about to say. At 27,
I went full time at going online, and
the same year,
I did my first ever Brazilian jujitsu
session.
Some of you might think I'm very good at
jujitsu because the footage that you're
watching now is nine years in the making.
I've been training jujitsu for as long as
I have been fully online.
For my first two years,
I had the shit kicked out of me.
I began at a gym where my path to
improving was to suffer.
I quit that gym because my coach
was legitimately a psychopath.
But I kept turning up,
I kept improving with tiny margins,
and I kept coming
back.
You don't see the nights where I'd walk
out the gym, sit on the floor,
too tired to even stand on my skateboard
and skateboard home.
I'd sit there defeated, sore, and I
was literally shaking from
overexertion.
I would have the shit kicked out of me by
all the higher belts.
But then as time went on,
I got my blue belt,
then I got my purple belt.
Now I've got my brown belt. Now,
nearly 10 years on, I can beat
95% of people in the entire sport.
But not because I'm special, not
because I'm athletic,
not because I'm talented,
but because of all the years that I
ate shit.
I know for a fact you've never seen a
video of me from 2014,
2015, 2016, or even 2017.
The same reason you've not
seen footage of me rolling as a white
belt, a blue belt, or a purple belt.
And I hope by now you're starting to see
the fucking parallels.
The reason I'll get my black belt in the
next 12 months is the same reason I make
millions of dollars online.
It's the same reason I've had any success.
It's because I know I am not special,
and at every opportunity where I can
eat shit, feel like a failure,
or feel insecure, all I need to do is
take that on the chin
and turn up the next day.
The lessons that the majority of you need
are in the tasks that you are avoiding.
It took me three years of posting every
single day to get one fucking
online client.
The landscape for you to win online
is much easier than it
ever was for me. So the good news is,
you are much closer to that point of
everything changing,
that extra 2K a month,
than you thought before you watched
this video. But the bad news is,
you don't get to get it easier than anyone
else, and you have to eat shit
and fucking suffer and suck it up.
I still remember the cold winter evenings
in the Budget Gym in Bracknell, where I'd
set three posts to go out,
one at 7:00 a.m., one at midday,
one at 5:00 p.m.
I'd come home after rugby training,
and I'd lost three followers.
I had so many opportunities to quit,
and I didn't.
And I'm sorry, but the reason
that I could be doing better than you
is because
you're just being a bit of a fucking
pussy.
And if you get over that, well,
it's fucking awesome on the other side.
Sign up, give me 30 days,
I'll improve your business.
I'm going to do it for free.
It's all I'm asking.
If you enjoyed this video,
you're going to love this one.